STEFANO CASTRO TOGNINI

Oak Ridge National Laboratory

@ togninis@ornl.gov

Stognini

in stognini



Research Scientist at Oak Ridge National Laboratory mainly working on Celeritas, a GPU Monte Carlo (MC) detector simulation code for High Energy Physics (HEP) that will enable the use of DOE's Leadership Computing Facilities—such as Frontier and Summit—by HEP experiments. In the past I was a collaborator on MINOS and NOvA, managed by Fermi National Accelerator Laboratory (Fermilab). These are long-term multi-million dollar endeavors built to understand the nature of neutrinos and answer fundamental questions related to astrophysics, dark matter, and more. My 7+ years of experience, working with diversified teams led to many published data analyses, all developed using C++, Python, ROOT, shell scripting, massive parallel computing, and MC simulations. Software development is managed using GIT, allied with automated code referencing (Doxygen). Production of technical documentation is routinely done. Finally, I have experience teaching at undergraduate level, mentoring graduate students, presenting technical seminars, and talking to the public at science outreach events.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Research Scientist

Scalable Algorithms and Coupled Physics

Computational Sciences and Engineering Division

Oak Ridge National Laboratory

2023 − Present

Oak Ridge (TN), U.S.

Postdoctoral Research Associate

HPC Methods for Nuclear Applications

Nuclear Energy and Fuel Cycle Division

Oak Ridge National Laboratory

2019 − 2023

Oak Ridge (TN), U.S.

COLLABORATIONS

Celeritas Project

github.com/celeritas-project

2020 - Present

ORNL

A GPU Monte Carlo particle transport code for HEP experiments.

DOE **CODE**: 10.11578/dc.20221011.1

URL Muon Detector Project

2020 - Present

ORNL

A compact muon detector apparatus developed to test and validate new non-destructive techniques for geological disposal safety assessments (GDSA).

NO ν **A Experiment**

% novaexperiment.fnal.gov

2013 − 2018

♀ Fermilab / ANL / UFG

Leading author of Phys. Rev. D 99, 122004.

• Contributed to Phys. Rev. D 104, 012014.

MINOS/MINOS+ Experiment

% www-numi.fnal.gov

2011 - Present

♀ Fermilab / ANL / UFG

Contributed to Phys. Rev. D 91, 112006 / Phys. Rev. D 93, 052017.

PUBLICATIONS

SOFT SKILLS

Teaching Mentoring Science outreach

Portuguese (native) **English** Italian French



HARD SKILLS

Technical skills

Data analysis Monte Carlo simulation

Data structuring Parallel computing

Programming & scripting languages

C/C++ | Python | SQL | Shell **ETFX**

Frameworks, libraries & tools

art | GIT Doxygen Geant4 **ROOT CORSIKA** Spack LSF **TORQUE**

EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Physics - High Energy Physics

Federal University of Goias

Funding: CAPES, CNPq, ANL

2012 − 2018

♀ Goiania (GO), Brazil

DOE OSTI www.osti.gov/biblio/1468447

M.Sc. in Physics - High Energy Physics

Federal University of Goias

Funding: CAPES, Fermilab

2010 − 2012

♀ Goiania (GO), Brazil

B.Sc. in Physics

Federal University of Goias

≅ 2005 − 2010

♀ Goiania (GO), Brazil